# **CHETAN DESAI**

Email: chetandesai2488@gmail.com

Mob: - +91 9428100659

iOS Developer

# **PROFILE**



Expert in Enterprise and Mobile application development over **5.0 years**. Skilled at leading teams, mentoring team members, design and requirements. Demonstrated ability to understand and improve legacy code and to become proficient at new technologies quickly.

### **EXPERIENCE**

I have conceptualized, designed, developed and deployed various types of applications for iOS based mobile phones. I have created handset specific user interface (UI) for iPhone and iPad. I have also researched on application acceptance and solicited feedback from users to make the new and existing applications more user friendly.

### SKILLS

Programming Language: Objective-C, Swift

**Technologies:** Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, Firebase, MVC, MVVM

**Database:** SQLite, MySQL, Firebase real-time **Operating System:** Mac OS, Windows XP/7/8 **Testing and Integration Tools:** Bit bucket, GitHub

**Development Tools:** Xcode SDK

### WORK EXPERIENCE

1. Keshav InfoTech: - 16 Feb, 2015 to 26 Feb, 2016

**Designation: - iOS developer** 

Job Profile: - Responsible for designing and develop & RND iOS application in native.

#### 2. CMExpertise InfoTech Pvt. ltd.

01 Mar, 2016 to 05 Dec, 2019

# **Designation: - iOS developer**

Job Profile: - Lead programmer & handling new project, presenting new ideas to potential client. Requirement gathering and analytics. To collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design and ship new features. To design, develop, test and implement an iOS application as well as continue production of new versions of the application. To design solutions independently. Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability and general reliability. Work on bug fixing and improving application performance. Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

#### 3. i can infotech

23 Nov, 2020 to Till date

# **Designation: - Senior iOS developer**

Job Profile: - Knowledge of Swift, Objective C, iOS, and other mobile frameworks. Analyze, optimize, and improve the code base. Work on bug fixing and improving application performance. Collaborate with other developers; provide mentorship to members of the team, and work to efficiently achieve the team's goals. Effective team player and good communicator.

# **EDUCATION**

**B.E.IT** (Bachelor of engineering in Information Technology), Hemchandracharya North Gujarat University, Patan, Gujarat, India, July-2011.

**HSC,** A.K. Vidhyamandir, Bavla, Gujarat, India, March-2006. **SSC,** A.K. Vidhyamandir, Bavla, Gujarat, India, March-2004.

# **WORK\_SUMMARY:**

App name : Golf GPS – FreeCaddie

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Core Bluetooth, Core Location, FacebookSDK, GoogleSDK, Google Map, SQLite, Audio player, Text to speech, XML Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

- https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/free-golf-gps-freecaddie/id303296542?ls=1&mt=8
- ➤ https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/golf-gps-rangefinder-audio/id1015822472?ls=1&mt=8
- https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/golf-gps-freecaddie-pro/id306070913?ls=1&mt=8

FreeCaddie is the completely free golf GPS rangefinder for your iPhone. With over 30,000 mapped golf courses available you'll be able to just download a course and play golf. Now includes Audio updates to the centre of the green when you reach your ball. A great way to use the app "hands-free"! Use FreeCaddie for as long as you like. If you decide you want more you can upgrade to FreeCaddie Pro which provides more detailed scoring and statistics, overhead Map view of the course, a multi-player Scorecard and more.

App name : **Sports.Connect** 

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Swift 4.0, Push Notification, Core Location, Localization

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/app/sports.connect/id1453284519?mt=8

Description: -

Find players in minutes! Football, cricket, basketball and more. Let us help you connect with the sporting community in UAE.

App name : Sugar Cube

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Hardware device interaction using Zeroconf-Bonjour & Manage Wi-Fi network, NSNetServiceBrowser, NSNetService, JSON,

AFNetworking, LGPlusButtonsView Library, GoogleAnalytices, MessageUI

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/sugarcube-by-sweetvinyl/id1257973704?mt=8

#### Description: -

The Sugar Cube is a line of all-in-one vinyl noise removal and recording/playback components. The Sugar Cube SC-1 and SC-2 are the first audiophile-grade products to enable non-destructive click & pop removal on any vinyl LP record in real-time. This app lets you control the Sugar Cube.

App name : Fanalyze

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Swift 4.0, AAChartkit

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/fanalyze/id1436233274?mt=8

#### Description: -

Fanalyze to speed up Fantasy Sports Research and Analysis by using Search. Search a NFL player and get player profile, news, status, stats, projections, graphs, player related twitter feeds and more.

App name : Shreeji Food

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Swift 4.0, Push Notification, Core Location Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link

https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/shreeji-food/id1449839353?mt=8

#### Description: -

Indian Cooking Recipes Video app has the largest collection of Indian Foods and Recipes.

App name : Orazio-Anelli

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Push Notification, Core Location Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/orazio-anelli/id1363911786?mt=8

#### Description: -

The Orazio Anelli app allows you to keep in touch with your Orazio Anelli salon and discover all the new trends to inspire you for your next look.

App name : GoGolf GPS

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Core Bluetooth, Core Location,

FacebookSDK, GoogleSDK, Google Map, Localization, SQLite, Audio player, Text to speech,

**XML** 

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

➤ https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gogolf-gps/id1261263097?ls=1&mt=8

### Description: -

This app is fully operational. Lower Your Score-Paired with your mobile device, GoGolf GPS audibly gives you the distance to the centre of the green and/or your last shot...from anywhere on the course! Over 30,000 courses supported and with over 35 different languages, both audio and written. No more guessing - Go Golf GPS will teach you to trust the distances you can hit your clubs with confidence.

App name : **D-Sport** 

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Core Bluetooth, Core Location
Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/d-sport/id1169979276?mt=8

D-SPORT is monitor live boost pressure and peak boost pressure. D-SPORT take full control of your engine's performance with the DINANTronics SPORT Tuner.

App name : Flowmaster Delta Boost

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Core Bluetooth, Core Location
Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/flowmaster-delta-boost/id1173507394?ls=1&mt=8

### Description: -

Flowmaster delta boost is monitor live boost pressure and peak boost pressure. It take full control of your engine's performance with the Flowmaster DELTA BOOST Performance Tuner.

App name : iModelScout

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/imodelscout/id359903193?ls=1&mt=8

#### Description: -

iModelScout is Searching for YOU OR YOUR BFF! Have you dreamed of being a Model or do you have a great eye to be a Talent Scout?

App name : **Dr. Salam Abu Shaaban** 

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, YouTube player, Push notification Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Link :

https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/id998078338?mt=8

#### Description: -

This application provide information, tips medical multi relating to anti-aging and herbal medicine.

App name : InsttaOrder

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Push notification, Firebase real-time

integration

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Instta Order is the easiest restaurant POS system to use, so staff are able to turn more tables and move lines faster, helping to increase sales. Instta Order is quick to learn and train allowing restaurants to save time onboarding new staff and training existing ones. Instta Order enhances the FOH staff and managers' ability to better serve customers, resulting in higher tips and a superior customer experience.

App name : Instta Service

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Push notification, Firebase real-time

integration

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

#### Description: -

Instta service is the easiest hotel room, bar, restaurant and reception POS system to use, so customer, staff are able to turn more tables and move lines faster, helping to increase sales. Instta service is quick to learn and train allowing room, bar, restaurant and reception to save time onboarding new staff and customer and training existing ones. Instta service enhances the staff and managers ability to better serve customers, resulting in higher tips and a superior customer

experience.

App name : CRMSky

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Local notification, Plivo VOIP SDK,

SQLite, Audio player, Audio Toolbox

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Description: -

CRMSky is a free VOIP calls application.

App name : **POS** 

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Objective-C, Push notification, SQLite, PDF Reader,

PayPal, Stripe, MessageUI

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Description: -

At the POS, the merchant would calculate the amount owed by the customer and indicate the amount and may prepare an invoice for the customer.

App name : **Deals Now** 

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Swift 4.0, Push notification, Core Location
Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Deals Now helps you save money through awesome deals on everything near you! Restaurants, Lunch / Dinner, Buffets, Spas and Salons, Gaming & Bowling, Water Parks, Amusement Parks, Things to do, and the list is endless - you name it and Deals Now has the best deals & discounts on it.

App name : VCare

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Swift 4.0, Push notification, Core Location, Google Map

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

### Description: -

User can see list of donor post with Location, Add Your Donor & Collector Post(Add Location, date, time, category, User can like & unlike collector post and see location on map, User can see Need, Donor, Collector profile. Login with Facebook and Gmail.

App name : JWChat(social & chatting application)

Relevant Technology : Xcode, Swift 4.0, Push notification, Core Location, Google Map,

Firebase real-time database integration

Role : Key developer to implement Design and development

Description: -

JWChat App provide add moment & share your friends. Like and edit, delete moment. Find near by friends, Sync contact, Chat with near by friends.

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : Chetan Bhagwanbhai Desai Father Name : Bhagwanbhai Valjibhai Rabari Mother Name : Takhiben Bhagwanbhai Rabari

Permanent Address : 7, Sundaram Park, Nr. Girls school, Bavla-382220, Dist-

Ahmeadabad, Gujarat, India.

Date of Birth : 24th Oct 1988

Marital status : Single
Nationality : India
Passport : Yes

PAN number : BDSPD9803N

LinkedIn profile : www.linkedin.com/in/chetan-desai-324b5b93

I consider myself familiar with iOS application development and Information Technology Engineering aspects. I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Chetan B. Desai